Dominic Walker

Senior Front End Developer at Uber

dom.walker1987@gmail.com

Summary

Senior Front End Developer proficient working for business of different size. I've gained great experience working with a range of clients, as well as working in house in a product based environment. I'm passionate about creating user friendly interfaces using the latest technologies and love to keep up to date with the shifting trends of the web development landscape.

Specialties include: HTML5, CSS3, Sass, OO Javascript, Responsive, ES6

Experience

Senior Front End Developer at Uber

June 2014 - Present

- Build mobile first responsive websites on frameworks and platforms that suit the clients business and technical needs
- Own the development and technical relationship for a number of Uber's clients
- Work with these clients to improve website performance using metrics and testing
- Re-defined the frontend boilerplate, tech stack, and coding standards
- Develop frontend single page applications
- Work with the UX and design teams to build interactive prototypes to validate our approach

Sites I have worked on in my time at uber:

http://www.gtnexus.com

http://expert.gtnexus.com

http://www.innovationlab.eastman.com

http://www.landstar.com

http://www.luciamagnani.com

http://www.kfccareers.co.uk

I have also completed work for clients on internal systems and sites that are not listed above.

Technologies used: Backbone, OO Javascript, Angular, ReactJS, Redux, Drupal, PHP, ASP.NET, HTML5, CSS3, ES6, Grunt, Gulp, Webpack

Junior Front End Developer at Karmarama

April 2013 - May 2014 (1 year 1 month)

- Maintained and updated clients large high traffic sites
- Worked for a number of clients on responsive email campaigns
- Built short life advertising campaign sites with integration to social media platforms
- Worked with a major international banking group to re-build an internal presentation system using Backbone and Marionette

Technologies used: Backbone, Marionette, OO Javascript, Drupal, PHP, HTML5, CSS3, Grunt

Junior Web Developer at House of Fraser

May 2012 - April 2013 (11 months)

- Worked maintaining and improving the company's large eCommerce site
- Worked closely with the UX team to create interactive prototypes for new site features and journeys
- I created a responsive module HTML email template system to speed up production
- Helped develop new pages and site areas
- Set up site content updates for large brand and holiday events

Technologies used: Javascript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Web Designer / Developer at Yell

November 2010 - May 2012 (1 year 6 months)

- Building websites in WordPress and Websplanet using HTML5 and CSS3, making sure SEO best practices are followed
- Front-end development using jQuery
- Creating designs in a target driven environment
- Creating training material and feedback for the offshore teams
- Appointed as design QA to make sure the teams designs are up to a high enough standard
- Carrying out testing on the Yellsites products to find coding and development flaws
- Communicating with clients about their ideas and translating them into a website that meets their criteria

Technologies used: Javascript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Director//Web Designer/Secretary

August 2008 - October 2009 (1 year 2 months)

Set up and ran a company in conjunction with the university SPEED scheme.

- Developed a number of websites, including a Magento driven ecommerce website
- Total £13,000 turnover over 1 year, where freelance work continued with multiple clients after the company dissolved

Education

Staffordshire University

BSc Film Production Technology, Film Technology, Post Production, Design, Web Design, 2006 - $2010\,$

Dominic Walker

Senior Front End Developer at Uber

dom.walker1987@gmail.com



Contact Dominic on LinkedIn